

Ray Berry

SUMMARY - iOS Developer

I am a highly experienced IT professional with a background in financial, retail and automotive industries. I've cross trained into iOS development with five years experience in Swift and Xcode. I am also a qualified Scrum Master. Please review my App portfolio in the link just below.



rayberryrb@gmail.com



07951 010595



App Portfolio



Bourne, Nr Peterborough

in_linkedin.com/in/ray-berry

KEY SKILLS

- iOS Developer Swift 5 Xcode 14 Github/GitLab Firebase CoreData Realm CoreML ARKit
- Rest API
 JSON
 Cocoapods
 Swift Packages
 SwiftUI
 Combine
 MVC
 MVVM
 Tableviews
- Collection Views
 SpriteKit
 Sourcetree
 CI/CD
 Xcode cloud
 User Authentication (FaceID, TouchID)
- Agile Scrum Master-PSM1 Project Management Jira Confluence Sprint planning
- UI/UX Design Wireframes Mock-ups Miro/Adobe Human Interface Guidelines
- Testing XCTest XCUITest
- ERP process integration
 B2B
 EDI
 XML
 AS2

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

iOS Developer - Blue Light Card

11/2019 - Present

Leicester, UK

- iOS developer of the Blue Light Card and Defence Discount apps.
- With over 2 million users, 4.8 out 5 app star rating, 260K 5 star ratings and 99.98% crash free.
- Exposure to Firebase events, push notifications, ML vision text recognition and Crashlytics.
- Use of Browerstack for app testing and Xcode Cloud for CI/CD integration.
- Knowledge of SwiftUI, combine and async/await.
- Knowledge Rest APIs, bearer token and multiform-posts.
- Use of XCTest and XCUTest.

iOS Developer - Cross trained

10/2017 - 11/2019

Bourne, UK

- Good knowledge of Swift 5 and Xcode 10.
- Developed the following Apps:
 - FileIT Inventory Management to track inventory to assist with home insurance or moving house. Uses Core Data, User Authentication and Core Graphics Animation.
 - Weather using Rest APIs, JSON and GPS location data to retrieve weather data.
 - To do list using Realm and Core Data to store shopping/to do list persistent data.
 - Chat using Firebase Cloud Services to register users and store chat data.
 - Flower classification using CoreML and the Caffe model to take photos of flowers to confirm the type of flower that is in the photo. Experience of CreateML to develop my own models.
 - Augmented Reality Tape measure using ARkit and Scenekit to measure 3D objects.
 - Video Streaming using HLS (Http Live Streaming) to showcase apps that I have developed.
- Agile qualified Scrum Master PSM1 certification.
- UI/UX Design experience of creating wireframes and mock-ups.

Development Manager

BGL Group Ltd

2012 - 10/2017

Peterborough UK

- Home of Comparethemarket.com, I successfully managed an IT development team of between four and eight people delivering internal financial insurance software development projects.
- Scrum Master for a development team. Knowledge and use of Scrum Agile processes including: sprint planning; daily stand-ups; two week sprint cycles; sprint reviews and retrospectives.
- Understanding and using the Atlassian tools: Jira and Confluence to manage sprints and update product backlog.

NEU IS Supply Services Lead

Reckitt Benckiser

2010 - 2012

Hull, UK

- Managing a cross-section of IT projects ranging from senior management reporting, cost reduction exercises, automation of business interfaces between JDE and Siebel; Manugistics and EDI packages.
- The project management encompassed resource allocation, budget control, prioritisation, risk analysis, project delivery and post implementation reviews.

European IS Supply Services Lead

Reckitt Benckiser

2006 - 2009

Hull, UK

Project managing teams as well as working with external off-shore support from Bangalore, India to ensure implementation of a demand planning tool (Manugistics 7.2) across sixteen countries in Europe. Managing project budget for Europe for over £1m for Manugistics rollouts.

EDI Senior Business Analyst

Reckitt Benckiser

2003 - 2006

Hull, UK

- I was responsible for EDI within Europe for RB. I was responsible for a team of five supporting the EDI infrastructure within seventeen countries across Europe.
- Consultancy role on EDI interface design and development into JD Edwards.
- Good EDI mapping experience using Inovis TLI series visual mapper. Mapping in TRADACOM, EDIFACT, ANSI X12 and EANCOM subsets i.e HANCOM. Written code in RPG for interface routines.

Freelance EDI Consultant

Freelance

1998 - 2003

Chiswick/Slough, UK

EDI integration specialist in BPCS and JD Edwards using Harbinger /Inovis Trusted Link I series EDI interfacing products and RPG.

EDUCATION

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

GitHub Repository

Cambridge College of Arts and Technology

Swift

COBOL

HND in Software Engineering

RPG

Knowsley Tertiary College OND in Computer Studies • C

Higherside Comprehensive School

7 O' levels including Maths, English and Computer Studies

ACHIEVEMENTS

2014 - Round Table President (Bourne)

2014 - Burghley Rat Race 20 Mile Assault course

2008 - Round Table Chairman (Bourne)

2006 - London Marathon

2005 - BUPA North Half Marathon

Qualified Scrum Master - PSM1